Guide to the Records of the South Park Conservatory Theatre, 1974-1995 CTC.1995.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
South Park Conservatory Theatre Records
1974-1995
CTC.1995.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
6.0 linear feet (9 boxes)
This collection documents the South Park Conservatory Theatre, a community and educational theatre group, from its beginnings as the South Park Summer Theatre in 1974 until it became the South Park Theatre in 1995. The production history for both its main stage and children's theatre shows is captured through legal agreements, correspondence, publicity materials, newspaper clippings, programs, and production photographs.
South Park Conservatory Theatre (Pa.).
History
The South Park Conservatory Theatre (SPCT) grew out of the South Park Summer Theatre, a community group that produced one show each summer between 1974 and 1976. Performances were held at the South Park High School auditorium. South Park High School drama teacher Shirley Custer and her former student Ronald A. Wisniski expanded this program by co-founding the SPCT in 1977. Under Custer's direction, this nonprofit corporation sought to promote the theatre arts among the area's adults and children, as well as to provide educational opportunities through workshops and an apprentice program for high school students.
The SPCT moved its productions to the South Park Fairgrounds, performing on average four main stage shows per season in the Frank Curto Horticultural Building as well as two or three children's theatre shows at the adjacent outdoor natural stage. Due to its interest in providing a wide range of performance opportunities, the SPCT sometimes hosted productions by other local theatre companies including Iron Clad Agreement, Two Star Productions, and Jackie Nicoll Productions. After Custer's death in February 1995, the role of executive director passed to local actress Audrey Castracane and the organization's name was changed to the South Park Theatre for legal and tax purposes.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of three series. The scrapbooks in the first series are arranged chronologically from 1974 to 1995. Each year includes materials such as season brochures, correspondence, agreements, programs, and photographs relating to main stage shows. The second series, children’s theatre materials, contains programs, flyers, photographs, news clippings, and play scripts from children’s theatre productions between 1977 and 1994. A group of ground plans, front elevations, and artistic renderings executed by Alfred Kirschman in 1977 and between 1984 and 1992 for main stage productions comprise the third series.
Arrangement
Series I. Scrapbooks, 1974-1995
Series II. Children's Theatre Materials, 1977-1994
Series III. Scenic Designs, 1977, 1984-1992
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of South Park Conservatory Theatre in July 1995.
Previous Citation
South Park Conservatory Theatre Records, 1974-1995, CTC.1995.02, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Custer, Shirley; Kirschman, Alfred; South Park Conservatory Theatre (Pa.).; South Park Summer Theatre (Pa.).; South Park Theatre (Pa.).; Actors and actresses; Children's theater -- Pennsylvania -- South Park (Township); Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- South Park (Township); South Park (Pa.: Township); Theater; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- South Park (Township); Theater -- Production and direction -- Pennsylvania -- South Park (Township); Theater programs
- Scrapbooks, 1974-1995; I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains seven scrapbooks, arranged chronologically, covering the SPCT's main stage production and organizational history from 1974 through 1995. Each year follows the same format: season brochure; documents, agreements, correspondence, and miscellaneous production materials; newspaper clippings; and show programs followed by production photographs.
  - Scrapbooks, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbooks, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
- Children's Theatre, 1977-1994; II.
  This series includes programs, flyers, photographs, news clippings, and play scripts pertaining to the SPCT's children's theatre productions from 1977 to 1994. The programs and flyers are arranged chronologically, as are the photographs when identifying information allows. The news clippings and play scripts are in their original order.
  - Programs and flyers, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Programs and flyers, 1981-1985 (Folder 2)
  - Programs and flyers, 1986-1989 (Folder 3)
  - Programs and flyers, 1990-1994 (Folder 4)
  - Production photographs, 1982 (Folder 5)
  - Production photographs, Song of Sixpence, 1983 (Folder 6)
  - Production photographs, The Liberated Dragon, 1984 (Folder 7)
  - Production photographs, Charlotte's Web, 1985 (Folder 8)
  - Production photographs, Dorothy and the Wizard of Oz, 1985 (Folder 9)
  - Production photographs, Pinocchio, 1986 (Folder 10)
  - Photographs of publicity posters, 1988-1993 (Folder 11)
  - Unidentified production and miscellaneous photographs, undated (Folder 12-16)
  - News clippings, undated (Folder 17)
  - Play Scripts, The Golden Goose and Once Upon a Shoe, undated (Folder 18)
- Scenic Designs, 1977-1992; III.
  Ground plans, elevations, and artistic renderings of sets for main stage shows done by Alfred Kirschman in 1977 and between 1984 and 1992. Media include pencil, pen, chalk, marker, and acrylic paint.
  - Artistic renderings, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ground plans, elevations, and artistic renderings, 1984-1989 (Folder 2)
  - Ground plans and elevations, 1991 (Folder 3)
  - Ground plans, elevations, and artistic renderings, 1992 (Folder 4)